<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/</link>
   <description>ASARPhiB: Simple Almost Rigorous Philosophical Blog<br /><small>Or just a hASARdous Philosophical Blog</small></description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ ASARPhiB ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ ASARPhiB: Simple Almost Rigorous Philosophical Blog<br /><small>Or just a hASARdous Philosophical Blog</small> ]]>
   </description>
   <link>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/</link>
   <image>
   <url>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/assets/images/ASARPhiB_logo.svg.png</url>
   <title>ASARPhiB</title>
   <link>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Open Government</title>
	  <link>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/open-government</link>
		
				
						<author>Jonathan Bennett</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-09-03T17:30:00-04:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/open-government</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>“Democracy” initially stands for: the power to the people.
Do you feel like you are in control?
If you answered no, learn what Open Government is and why we should adopt it !</p>

<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>

<p>Most of the modern democracies are in fact some form of <em>representative</em> democracies.
Meaning that the people elects representatives that will then rule the country by creating, applying and interpreting laws.
This leads to situation where the people actually express its will only by electing representatives, so approximately once per year.</p>

<p>Now, why wouldn’t we form some <em>direct</em> democracies ?
The main argument, few centuries ago, was that it was not possible to manage a whole population voting on each issue.
And this was fine then.
But is it now ?</p>

<h1 id="opinion-and-argumentation">Opinion and Argumentation</h1>

<p>In my opinion, of course, it is not: today democracies are obsolete.
We have the necessary means to create more direct democracies, which I consider better.</p>

<h2 id="why-are-more-direct-democracies-better">Why are more direct democracies better?</h2>

<p>I consider direct democracies to be better for many reasons and here are a few:</p>
<ul>
  <li>You might agree on most subject with the person you elect to represent you but what about the other subjects ? Wouldn’t it be easier (except for organizational reasons) to represent yourself… well yourself ?</li>
  <li>The person you elected to represent you is generally elected for a time span (often a few years). What if that person changes with time ? You cannot tell what he/she will be in 2 or three years.</li>
  <li>Most of the politicians come from higher social classes. This is problematic, because the population might not be represented equitably.</li>
  <li>etc.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="why-more-direct-democracies-instead-of-direct-democracies">Why <em>more</em> direct democracies instead of direct democracies?</h2>

<p>In think that specialization, to some extend, is great idea and beneficent tool.
Following that reasoning, I would say that there are complicated subjects and decisions about those should be delegated to groups of experts specialized in that subject.
Also, it would be impossible to have the people vote on <em>every</em> issues a government faces.
In my view, neither extreme is good and we are at the representative extreme.</p>

<h2 id="what-now-">What Now ?</h2>

<p>OK, so more direct democracies are probably better.
What do we do now?</p>

<h1 id="wait-for-it-open-government">Wait for it… Open Government</h1>

<p><img src="assets/images/posts/openGovernment-wordCloud.jpg" alt="Open Government Word Cloud" /></p>

<h2 id="definition">Definition</h2>

<p><em>Note: the definition below might not correspond to the generally accepted definition, or put emphasis on different parts.</em></p>

<p><strong>Open Government</strong>: An Open Source movement that aims to make government data open to the public and to promote civic participation.</p>

<h2 id="what-it-could-be">What it Could Be</h2>

<p>Imagine that your government creates an app or website which allows you to vote, to obtain official dataset easily, to complete administrative procedures and to report problems (like pothole, broken stuffs, etc.).
Individuals’ life would be easier, contacts with the government would make society more efficient, resources would be better used and transparency would make it harder for corruption to exist.
This is what Open Government could look like.</p>

<p>You can even think it one step further.
For example, if there existed a platform where you could download governmental dataset, then you could imagine having citizen or universities doing data mining on it to find ways to optimize how resources are used.</p>

<h1 id="a-little-example">A Little Example</h1>

<p>A few months back, I traveled to Europe.
During my trip, I visited a few countries, one of which is quite relevant to the thematic at hand: Switzerland.</p>

<p>This little country has a very peculiar system and the Swiss people <strong>votes on average four times a year on elections but also on policies and so-called initiatives</strong>.
My point being: There exists some countries where a more direct democracy is used and it works.
In fact it works greatly for Switzerland:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Switzerland has a stable, prosperous and high-tech economy and enjoys great wealth, being ranked as the wealthiest country in the world per capita in multiple rankings. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Switzerland">Wikipedia, 04-09-2018</a></p>
</blockquote>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Open (Source), a Revolution</title>
	  <link>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/open-source</link>
		
				
						<author>Jonathan Bennett</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-03-04T07:34:00-05:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>http://localhost:4000/ASARPhiB/open-source</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The open source movement is an alternative way of working and cooperating that could very well change our society.
It is based on cooperation instead of exchanges and is already a standard in the digital world.
But many applications of it are possible especially in the real world.</p>

<h1 id="the-open-source-a-revolution">The Open (Source), a Revolution</h1>

<h2 id="back-to-the-origins-the-open-source-movement">Back to the Origins: The Open Source Movement</h2>

<h3 id="a-quick-definition-of-open-source">A Quick Definition of Open Source</h3>

<p>An open source software must provide the four following liberties:</p>
<ol>
  <li>The liberty to use the software</li>
  <li>The liberty to view the source code (useful if you want to learn how to code for example)</li>
  <li>The liberty to modify the code (so that you can take a program and modifz it in order to make it match your exact needs)</li>
  <li>The liberty to distribute your modified version of the code</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="the-main-characteristic-of-open-source">The Main Characteristic of Open Source</h2>

<p>The whole idea behind open source software is that a program should rely on a community of users and programmers.
This community can then propose changes, implement them and make them available to all!
By doing that you give the control back to the persons that use the software.
That way, you are certain that the software corresponds to the needs of the persons using it.
And if the community is big enough it also ensure great quality of code, a lot of support provided by more experienced user to least experienced ones, rapid improvements and adaptation to newer needs, etc.</p>

<p>In a somewhat broader sense, one could consider an open source software as simply a cooperation between human beings.
By improving the program, you will not gain money but you will be cooperating with humanity.</p>

<h2 id="examples-of-open-source-software">Examples of Open Source Software</h2>

<p>Open source software are everywhere.
Here are a few examples:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The linux operating system</li>
  <li>The android operating system</li>
  <li>Firefox</li>
  <li>LibreOffice</li>
  <li>Gimp (used for photo editing)</li>
  <li>Blender (to create animated movies)</li>
  <li>etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>In fact, at least 70% of the Internet is run by open source software (the vast majority of the computers powering Internet run Linux as operating system, most of the web server like Apache are open source, most of the protocols on the internet are open source, etc.).
Almost all programming languages are open source too.</p>

<p>Amongst non-open source software, one can find: The Apple ecosystem (iOs, Pages, Keynote, etc.), the Microsoft ecosystem (Windows, Microsoft Office, etc), the Adobe ecosystem (Photoshop, InDesign, etc.).</p>

<h2 id="fine-but-why-should-i-care">Fine, But Why Should I Care?</h2>

<p>Open source software is probably of little concern for you, but the ideas it conveys certainly are not!</p>

<p>From the open source originated a lot of other open movements like:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Open Hardware (Arduino and RaspberryPi for example)</li>
  <li>Open Beer (open beer receipes)</li>
  <li>Open Data (data available to all online to easily make statistics or researches)</li>
  <li>Open Science</li>
  <li>Open Government</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="a-revolution">A Revolution</h3>

<p>I believe that all those movements will transform our society in a very profound manner.
They highlight the fact that cooperation is a possible alternative to our system based on exchanges (can you imagine a world without money? Well, the people that created the open source apparently could!).
And with the rise of new technologies like the Internet, open alternative will be easier and easier to put in place.</p>

<p>For example, Open Government is a way of implying the people living in a society in their governance.
The idea is to facilitate the communication between the government and the people: more transparency from the government to the society, more inputs from the people to the government, etc.
This could simplify the democratic process and even increase it.</p>

<p>All in all I strongly hope that open source will impose itself and maybe even change our society!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
